Speaker: We all know that too much sugar and salt isn't good for us.
But do we really know how much sugar and salt are in
some of the things we eat and drink every day?
Let’s start with sugar.
According to the American Heart Association, the maximum healthy limit
for a woman is 24 grams of sugar a day. That’s just 6 teaspoons.
For a man, it is no more than 36 grams, which is 9 teaspoons.
Here we have an egg, a can of soda, a small bar of dark chocolate, and an apple.
How much sugar do you think they contain?
One of them has 35 grams of sugar.
That’s 11 grams more than the healthy limit for a woman in a day.
Which one do you think it is?
Yes, it’s the can of soda.
A can of soda has approximately 35 grams of sugar. That’s a lot.
And which has no sugar?
Of course, it’s the egg.
So what about the other two?
Which do you think has more sugar, the chocolate or the apple?
Surprisingly, it’s the apple.
The apple has approximately 23 grams of sugar. That’s a lot.
But it's fructose, a natural sugar.
And remember that fruit is also good for you, because it contains vitamin C.
The chocolate bar only has a little sugar, just 10 grams.
But remember: it’s dark chocolate, and it’s only a small bar.
What about salt? How much salt can we eat a day?
This time it's the same for men and women.
The answer is no more than 6 grams.
Here we have a small bag of chips, a bottle of olive oil,
a bottle of water, and a piece of bread.
So how much salt do they contain?
Which one has a lot of salt, and which one has none?
You may be surprised to hear that the one with a lot of salt is
the piece of white bread.
It has approximately 0.5 grams.
And which one has no salt?
No, it’s not the water, it’s
the olive oil.
It contains no salt, and as part of a Mediterranean diet, it’s very healthy.
So what about the other two?
Well, a small bag of chips has approximately 0.34 grams of salt.
And lastly, there is a little in the water.
Just 0.0023 grams.
So when you’re shopping, how do you know what to buy
to make sure it doesn’t have too much sugar or salt?
The answer is, always check the list of ingredients, and remember what your daily limit is.